<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Krzysztof Zbiciński - Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lorem lipsum, how to code frontend and don't go bonkers]]></description><link>http://zbic.in</link><image><url>https://zbicin.github.io/images/cover.png</url><title>Krzysztof Zbiciński - Blog</title><link>http://zbic.in</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 21:54:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://zbic.in/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Music Driven Development]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Back in the days, I tweeted few words about staying focused:</p>
</div>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-cards="hidden" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Pomodoro + chillstep music = really great focus. Give it a try.<a href="https://t.co/VPzTxT2ul5">https://t.co/VPzTxT2ul5</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/productivity?src=hash">#productivity</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/codinghard?src=hash">#codinghard</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/keyboardonfire?src=hash">#keyboardonfire</a></p>&mdash; Krzysztof Zbiciński (@zbicin) <a href="https://twitter.com/zbicin/status/697542362512363522">February 10, 2016</a></blockquote>
<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>After a year, I can broaden this statement and say that what gives me really great focus is <strong>music in general</strong>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Recently I&#8217;ve had to go through a tedious task of writing my master thesis. The vision of performing a long research and dedicating an infinite amount of hours to it was anything but motivating. Nevertheless I had to put myself together and eventually face the challenge.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The surprising game changer was listening to VNM&#8217;s album entitled <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/5oAuwOiJkJDMKFLSraNkAX">Halflajf</a>. In addition to regular breaks (whether performed according to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique">pomodoro technique</a> or not) it was the major factor that was driving my productivity.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The good thing about listening to an album is that you can set a pause after a particular song and/or after the whole album has been played. That way it is easier to remember about taking breaks, even if the keyboard is on fire and <em>you want only to add this one more feature and then you&#8217;ll definately take a break</em>. Most of the time <strong>I didn&#8217;t</strong>. I simply kept forgetting about it.</p>
</div>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Aalbum%3A5oAuwOiJkJDMKFLSraNkAX" width="100%" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Interestingly, I discovered that I have a set of music albums or Spotify playlists that I can listen to during literally the whole workday and don&#8217;t get bored. They include e.g. chillstep and latino music playlists as well as some albums from Kanye West (especially <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/1NRRN5RWwfuLmQdjshz0L7">The College Dropout</a>!), Limb Bizkit or Bob Marley. I haven&#8217;t determined what is their common part though. It&#8217;s not the genre nor the language, that&#8217;s for sure.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Well&#8230;&#8203; it&#8217;s seems that I&#8217;m a pioneer of the music driven development. ;)</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://zbic.in/2017/03/14/Music-Driven-Development.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://zbic.in/2017/03/14/Music-Driven-Development.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Daj się poznać]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Get Noticed]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Other]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Krzysztof Zbiciński]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Go home, JS: Observables, observables everywhere]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>Recently I&#8217;ve begun my journey in the 'Get Noticed' contest. Accordingly to my <a href="https://trello.com/b/wZ5ZrdZO">Trello board</a> which I described in the
<a href="http://zbic.in/2017/03/02/Go-home-JS-Setting-up-Trello-board-to-keep-things-organized.html">previous blog post</a> I started creating an MVP. In this early stage I have to get a basic quiz flow, which implies implementing a service that handles the logic of the game (serving questions, acknowledging answers, etc.). For this purpose, I&#8217;ve created a <code>GameService</code> service.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>TL;DR:</p>
</div>
<div class="imageblock">
<div class="content">
<img src="https://cdn.meme.am/cache/instances/folder36/500x/67734036.jpg" alt="67734036.jpg">
</div>
<div class="title">Figure 1. Believe it or not, someone actually created this meme and it wasn&#8217;t me.</div>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Since the <a href="http://reactivex.io/rxjs/">RxJS</a> became a standard in Angular 2 development, I thought it would be good to get more proficient in it. A service that handles game logic and exposes several properties that may change (the game status, score, current question) seemed to be a perfect training spot.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>If you want to see how it turned out, you can look up the file at GitHub. I am quite happy with the result, especially that it was my first attempt to use something more than only <code>subscribe</code> and <code>map</code> ;).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I can totally reccomend this <a href="https://gist.github.com/staltz/868e7e9bc2a7b8c1f754">Introduction to reactive programming you&#8217;ve been missing</a>, if you want to get to know this concept and jump on its hype train.</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://zbic.in/2017/03/08/Go-home-JS-Observables-observables-everywhere.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://zbic.in/2017/03/08/Go-home-JS-Observables-observables-everywhere.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Get Noticed]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Daj się poznać]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Krzysztof Zbiciński]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Go home, JS: Setting up Trello board to keep things organized]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>As you may already know, I&#8217;ve decided to <a href="http://zbic.in/2017/03/01/Lets-start-Get-Noticed.html">take part in the 'Get Noticed!' contest</a>.
The idea I want to realize is a quiz-like application with a competitive note.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>In order to get things organized, I&#8217;ve just set up a Trello board which is <a href="https://trello.com/b/wZ5ZrdZO/go-home-js">publicly visible</a>. I decided to go with a Kanban-style approach, which worked for me best in the past, especially in case of such a small, personal projects. The board is divided into four sections: Done, In progress, Todo and Backlog (which also serves as a place for meta information).</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The In progress column may be considered redundand, since probably it will contain only one card most of the time. Nevertheless, I like to see things moving so it needs to stay. ;)</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://zbic.in/2017/03/02/Go-home-JS-Setting-up-Trello-board-to-keep-things-organized.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://zbic.in/2017/03/02/Go-home-JS-Setting-up-Trello-board-to-keep-things-organized.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Get Noticed]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Daj się poznać]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Krzysztof Zbiciński]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Let's start 'Get Noticed!']]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I was thinking about joining the <a href="http://dajsiepoznac.pl">Get Noticed! (Daj Się Poznać!) competition</a> last year, but didn&#8217;t manage to find enough free time to do so. I couldn&#8217;t miss this opportunity again so this year I decided to take my chances. Briefly speaking, it is a contest for programmers during which you are obliged not only to write the code but also document your progress with blog posts and spread the word in social media. You can learn more on the <a href="http://dajsiepoznac.pl">contest&#8217;s page</a>.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The series of posts under the Get Noticed tag will be dedicated exactly for this purpose. I will describe the development, reasoning behind the decisions I will take (or no reasoning as well) and all of the other matters that are more or less connected with the project.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Speaking about the project, it will be a <strong>JavaScript quiz with a competitive note</strong>. The main use case of this application is during conferences, meetups or workshops (like <a href="http://nodeschool.io/lodz">NodeSchool</a>). The speaker will show the presentation with questions considering JavaScript and its <strike>fucked up</strike> <em>unique</em> features. The attendands are meant to give answers using their smartphones. Obvoiusly, a person that gives the most correct answers wins.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The code is <a href="https://github.com/zbicin/go-home-js">available on GitHub</a>, however there is not much there by now. If you are curious about the project progress and details concerning its implementation, stay tuned for next posts. According to the rules of the contest, there should be at least two of them per week, which means plenty of writing.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Keep your fingers crossed and let&#8217;s do this!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://zbic.in/2017/03/01/Lets-start-Get-Noticed.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://zbic.in/2017/03/01/Lets-start-Get-Noticed.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Get Noticed]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Daj się poznać]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Krzysztof Zbiciński]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>
